Guide to the Athletics Reference collection, 1888-2005
Duke University. University Archives
Athletics Reference collection 1888-2005
Duke University. University Archives
8.4 linear feet Extent: 8,500 Items
The Athletics Reference Collection contains files of clippings, articles and essays, printouts, publications, and other materials about Duke athletic programs.
UA.01.11.0011
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Athletics Reference collection materials were compiled from a variety of sources by University Archives staff for reference and research.
Collection Overview
The Athletics Reference Collection contains files of clippings, articles and essays, printouts, publications, and other materials about Duke athletic programs. Topics include revenue and non-revenue sports, cheerleaders, fan behavior, fundraising, the Hall of Fame, Duke Olympians and other athletes, and sports promotions. This collection was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research.
Subject Headings
College athletes -- North Carolina -- Durham; College sports -- North Carolina -- Durham; Duke University -- Basketball; Duke University -- Football; Duke University -- Sports -- History; Duke University. University Archives; Clippings
Related Material
Duke University Athletic Department. Office of Sports Information Records, 1932-.
Duke University Archives.
Blue Devil Reference Collection, 1972-.
Duke University Archives.
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  Collection Arrangement
  The collection is arranged into the following series: Subject files; Children's Cancer Classic; Men's Sports; Special Events; Sport's Schedules; and Women's Sports.
  - Subject Files (Box 1)
    - Academics (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - Athletic Council - History (Box 1)
    - Athletic Department (Box 1)
    - Athletic Directors and Heads of Physical Education (Box 1)
    - Atlantic Coast Conference (Box 1)
    - Athletics-Historical (Box 1)
    - Basketball Clinic (Box 1)
    - Biographical Clippings (Box 1)
    - Blue Angels tour guides, 1958 (Box 1)
    - Blue Devil Club, 1961-1965 (Box 1)
    - Budget and Finances (Box 1)
    - Budget and Fundraising (non-Iron Duke) (Box 1)
    - Cameron Crazies (Box 1)
    - Cameron Crazies - Student Papers (Box 1)
    - Camps (Box 1)
    - Cheerleaders (Box 1)
    - Clippings, general (Box 1)
    - Club Sports (2 folders) (Box 2)
      - Club Sports, Club football (Box 2)
      - Club Sports, Ice Hockey (Box 2)
    - Duke - Carolina Rivalry (Box 2)
    - Duke - Carolina Rivalry - Carlyle Cup (Box 2)
    - Duke Sports Calendar, 1983-1984; 1986-1987 (Box 2)
    - Duke University Athletic Association - Ticket Book, 1928 (Box 2)
    - Hall of Fame (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - Hockey Club, undated; 1987 (Box 2)
    - Intramural Sports Handbooks, 1941-1975 (Box 2)
    - Iron Dukes (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - Athletics, Krzyzewskiville, camping out, see building file, K-ville and Cameron (Box 2)
    - Lists Misc. (Box 2)
    - Olympians (Box 2)
    - Pep Rallies (Box 2)
    - Promotions (Box 2)
    - Promotions - Blue Devil Days (Box 2)
    - Retrenchment Controversy (Swimming and Fencing), 1982 (Box 2)
    - Sportline Duke [newsletter] (Box 2)
    - Sports Information Dept. (Box 2)
    - Sports at Duke (General Information, Philosophy of Sports Programs etc.) (Box 2)
    - Summer Day Camp. Sports Camps [except Basketball] (Box 2)
    - Victory Bell (Box 2)
  - Children's Cancer Classic (Box 3)
    - 1993, 1999, 2001 (Box 3)
    - Program, 1985 (Box 3)
    - Program, 1986 (Box 3)
    - Program, 1987 (Box 3)
    - Program, 1989 (Box 3)
    - Programs, 1990 (Box 3)
    - 1992 (Box 3)
    - 1974 (Box 3)
    - Clippings, 1975, 1976, 1977, 1978, 1979 (Box 3)
    - Program, 1980 (Box 3)
    - Program, 1985, clippings, circa 1986-2000 (Box 3)
    - Program, Horse Show, 1984 (Box 3)
    - Clippings, 1985 (Box 3)
    - Celebrity-Amateur Golf and Tennis Tournament, Programs, 1985-1992 (Box 3)
    - Horse Show, 1984 (Box 3)
    - Races, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Men's Sports (Box 4)
    - Baseball
      - Clippings, brochures, flyers, etc., circa 1910-1999 (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - Basketball
      - Announcements - Special games, ticket info, banquets, etc. (late 1980s, early 1990s) (Box 4)
      - Autographs (Box 4)
      - ACC Yearbooks, Basketball, 1990-1992 (Box 4)
      - Basketball's beginnings at Trinity College -- News Clippings, The Trinity Chronicle, 30 Jan. 1906; 6 March 1906 (Box 4)
      - Basketball Record, 1945 (Box 4)
      - Class of 1986 (Box 4)
      - Clippings, team pictures, prospectus, etc., 1979-2000 (9 folders) (Box 4)
      - Coaches
        - 1973-1980 (Box 4)
        - Mike K., [sampling of letters to]. 1985-1986 (Box 4)
      - Dixie Classic, 1955, 1957, 1958 (Box 4)
      - Duke Basketball Interactive CD-ROM, 1995 (Box 4)
      - "Duke's Full House of Court Kings," Life 28 Jan. 1966 (Box 4)
      - Final Four, 1986 (Box 4)
      - Helms Athletic Foundation: Collegiate Basketball Records, Pt. II, 1943 (Box 5)
      - History (2 folders) (Box 5)
      - Misc., (3 folders) (Box 5)
      - NCAA Championship, April 1991 (Box 5)
      - NCAA Championship, April 1992 (Box 5)
      - NCAA Championship, 2001 (Box 5)
      - NCAA Tourney, 1990; 1994; 1999; 2004 (Box 5)
      - Photographs, Individual, 1977-1979 (2 folders) (Box 5)
      - Players, Biographical (Box 5)
      - Post and Pre Season Play, 1978-circa 1986 (Box 5)
      - Printed Material (Box 5)
      - "Rhapsody in Blue," Duke Basketball Banquet Commemorative Program, April 20, 1992 (Box 5)
      - Retired Jerseys (Box 5)
      - Basketball and Football Clippings books, circa 1963-1965 (Box 6)
      - Score Books, 1937-1945 (Box 6)
      - The Secret Game/Scott Ellsworth (Box 6)
      - Sports Illustrated
        - 30 March 1964-6 Dec. 1965 (Box 6)
        - 20 Dec. 1965-1 April 1991 (Box 6)
        - 25 Nov. 1991-1 Feb. 1993 (Box 7)
        - Nov. 2000-April 2001 (Box 7)
        - Champs: Duke Blue Devils, 2000-2001 (Box 7)
        - 2001-2002 Season (Box 7)
        - 35mm Negatives of S.I. covers [for internal university use only] (Box 7)
        - Duke vs. UNC, Mar. 2004; Feb. 2005 (Box 7)
      - Ticket Info (Box 7)
      - Ticket Policy (Box 7)
    - Trinity College, Durham, N.C., Athletics, Basketball (Box 7)
    - Boxing (Box 8)
      - Lougee, George, "Ex-Boxer A Mann for All Sports Seasons," article on Al Mann in the Durham Morning Herald, 11 March, 1984 (Box 8)
    - Fencing (Men and Women's)
      - Clippings, brochures, flyers, etc., 1973-1992 (Box 8)
      - Post season Statistics, 1981-1990 (men); 1983-1991 (women) (Box 8)
    - Football
      - All-American Bowl, 1989 (Box 8)
      - Atkinson, Harold, Stadium opening, 1929 (Box 8)
      - Cerebral Palsy Game
        - 1950-1963 (Box 8)
        - 1967- (Box 8)
        - 1970 (Box 8)
      - Clippings, circa 1963-1965 (see Basketball, clippings) (Box 8)
      - Clippings, circa1950-2003 (Box 8)
      - Football Magazine, 1970 (Box 8)
      - History
        - Biographical (Box 8)
        - Clippings (2 folders) (Box 9)
        - Duke vs. UNC (Box 9)
        - Iron Dukes (Box 9)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 9)
        - Promotional (2 folders) (Box 9)
        - Trinity College, 1888-1924 (Box 9)
      - Khedive Shrine Oyster Bowl Game (25th Anniversary), 1971 (Box 9)
      - Illustrated Football Annual, 1931 (Box 9)
      - Intercollegiate Sports, 1931 Sept. 22, Sept. 29 (Box 9)
      - Miller, Patrick B. Slouching Toward a New Expediency: College Football and the Color Line During the Depression Decade, American Studies, 40:3 (Fall 1999) (2 copies) (Box 9)
      - Pelican Bowl, 1972, NCCU vs. Grambling (Box 10)
      - Rose Bowl, 1939
        - Blue Devil Special Train, 1939 (Box 10)
        - Clippings (3 folders) (Box 10)
        - Clippings - Harry Welch gift (2 folders) (Box 10)
        - Media Guide (Box 10)
        - Menus (Box 10)
        - Program (Box 10)
        - Sound recordings (information only) (Box 10)
        - Tournament of Roses Souvenir Book (Box 10)
        - 1939 - Ticket (Box 10)
      - Rose Bowl, 1942 (Box 11)
        - Clippings (2 folders) (Box 11)
        - Clippings, post 1942 (Box 11)
        - Contract (copy) (Box 11)
        - Correspondence, 1939-1941 (copies)Exhibit (Box 11)
        - Exhibit materials (Box 11)
        - Miscellany (Box 11)
        - Team List (Box 11)
        - Charles C. Haynes Collection (Box 11)
        - Photograph Brunnemer (Box 11)
        - Program (Box 11)
        - Rose Bowl, 1942 (in 1982 Rose Bowl program (Box 11)
        - Tickets (copies) (Box 11)
        - Trophy (Box 11)
        - 50th Reunion, 1992 (Box 11)
        - A Rose Bowl Transplanted by Patricia Evert (Box 11)
        - Sumner, Jim L. John Franklin Crowell, Methodism and the Football Controversy at Trinity College (Box 11)
        - Sumner, Jim L., The North Carolina Inter-Collegiate Foot-Ball Association:The Beginnings of College Football in North Carolina (Box 11)
    - Golf
      - Clippings, brochures, flyers, etc., 1962-1994 (2 folders) (Box 11)
    - Gymnastics
      - (see Gymnastics under Women's Sports) (Box 11)
    - Lacrosse
      - Clippings, brochures, flyers, etc., 1938-1999 (2 folders) (Box 11)
    - Soccer (Box 12)
      - Clippings, brochures, flyers, etc., 1935; 1946; 1976-2004 (17 folders) (Box 12)
    - Swimming (includes Men and Women's team; see also Women's Sports swimming)
      - Clippings, brochures, flyers, etc., 1950-1997 (2 folders) (Box 12)
    - Tennis
      - Clippings, brochures, flyers, etc., 1973-1994 (2 folders) (Box 12)
    - Badminton (Box 12)
    - Track/Cross County (Box 13)
      - Clippings, brochures, flyers, etc., 1973-1993 (Box 13)
      - Clippings, Cross County, 1972-1977 (Box 13)
      - Special Events, 1919-1982 (Box 13)
      - Track and Field Day, Trinity College, 1911-1912 (Box 13)
    - Wrestling
      - Clippings, brochures, flyers 1951-2003 (3 folders) (Box 13)
  - Special Events
    - American Olympic Committee, 1936 (Box 13)
    - Pan-Africa - USA International Track Meets, 16-17 July, 1971 (Box 13)
    - USA - Pan Africa West Germany International Track Meet, 1975 (Box 13)
    - USA - Pan-Africa International Track and Field Meet, 1994 (Box 13)
    - M.L. King International Freedom Games, 12 May 1973 (Box 13)
    - USSR-USA Track and Field Meet, July 5-6, 1974 (2 folders) (Box 13)
    - Lite Field and Track Meets, May 1979; June 1982 (Box 14)
    - 1980 Bid for Olympic Track and Field trials (Box 14)
    - U.S. Olympic Festival, 1987(Raleigh, NC) (Box 14)
    - NCAA Track and Field Championships, 1990 (Box 14)
  - Sports Schedules
    - Spring, 1947-1982 (Box 14)
    - Winter, 1948-1978 (Box 14)
  - Special Olympics World Games, 1999 (Box 14)
  - Women's Sports
    - General
      - Bibliography, 1998 (Box 14)
      - Clippings, 1974-1979 (Box 14)
      - Handbooks and Brochures, circa 1974-1978 (Box 14)
      - History (Box 14)
      - Title IX, Clippings, 1976-1999 (Box 14)
      - Woman's Athletic/Recreation Association, [handbooks] 1954; 1956; 1963-1964 (Box 14)
      - Women's Sports, undated, 1976 (Box 14)
      - Nereidian Club, 1968 (Box 14)
    - Basketball
      - ACC Tournament Program, 2004 (Box 14)
      - Braun, Amanda. Twenty-five years of Women's Varsity Intercollegiate Basketball at Duke University, 2000 (Box 14)
      - Clippings, brochures, flyers, etc., 1977-2001 (Box 14)
      - Duke vs. UNC [Ronald McDonald Classic] Program, 17 Feb. 1987 (Box 14)
      - Game program, 2003-2004 (Box 14)
      - Schedules, 1976-1988 (Box 14)
      - Schedules, 2007-2008 (Box 14)
      - Team photos, clippings, 1997- (Box 14)
      - NCAA Tournament, 1995 (Box 15)
    - Crew
      - Clippings, 1976; 1997-1999 (2 folders) (Box 15)
    - Fencing(see Fencing in Men's sports above) (Box 15)
    - Field Hockey
      - Clippings, brochures, media guides, 1976-1993 (2 folders) (Box 15)
    - Golf
      - Clippings, brochures, media guides, 1975-2001 (2 folders) (Box 15)
    - Gymnastics
      - Clippings, 1976-1984 (Box 15)
      - Clippings, brochures, 1977-1983 (Box 15)
    - Lacrosse
      - Clippings, 1996; 2001 (Box 15)
    - Soccer
      - Clippings, brochures, 1988-2001 (Box 15)
    - Swimming
      - Clippings, 1976-1978 (See also Swimming in Men's Sports above) (Box 15)
    - Tennis (Box 16)
      - Clippings, brochures, 1976-2001 (2 folders) (Box 16)
    - Track and Field/Cross Country (Box 16)
    - Volleyball
      - Clippings, brochures, 1976-1993 (2 folders) (Box 16)